<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Subject Guide on Topics in Actuarial, Insurance and Finance</title>
    <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Subject Guide on Topics in Actuarial, Insurance and Finance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eligibility and Requirements</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/Eligibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/Eligibility/</guid>
      <description>To view the eligibility and requirements, including prerequisites, corequisites, recommended background knowledge and core participation requirements for this subject, please see the University Handbook:
  ACTL20004 handbook  ACTL90021 handbook  See also Excel assumed knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Outcomes</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/SILO/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/SILO/</guid>
      <description>Subject Intended Learning Outcomes (SILO) #  To view the subject objectives and the generic skills you will develop through successful completion of this subject, please see the University Handbook.
ACTL20004 SILO #  The ACTL20004 subject intended learning outcomes (SILO) are as follows:
 Derive and apply results for simple stochastic models for investment returns. Describe and apply techniques for analysing a delay (or run-off) triangle and projecting the ultimate position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Activities</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/Activities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/Activities/</guid>
      <description>Lectures #  Lecture Times #  Lectures will be delivered live, in dual mode (both on Zoom and in person) in the following venue:
 [PG] FBE Theatre 2, Mondays, from 10:05am to 11:55am [UG] FBE Prest Theatre, Mondays, from 2.20pm to 4.05pm  Notes:
 Lectures and tutorials run in week 6 as normal. The mid-semester exam will be on Wednesday night. Details about readings are available below under &amp;ldquo;Subject Resources&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/Resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/Resources/</guid>
      <description>Website #  The current website contains (or links) to all the resources you need for the course (compare the following list with left hand side menu):
  Subject guide (you are reading it!)  Prerequisite knowledge: assumed knowledge in Excel  Utility theory (CM2 1.2): the contents covering Section 1.2 of the CM2 syllabus.  Reserving (CM2 5.2): the contents covering Section 5.2 of the CM2 syllabus.  Excel (CM2 Exam B): the contents covering the Excel component of the CM2 syllabus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessment</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/Assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-subject-guide/Assessment/</guid>
      <description>Assessment Overview #  Assessment structure #  Your assessment for this subject comprises the following:
  a 50 minute closed book mid-semester exam (15%)  an individual assignment (25%)  a 2 hour closed book final exam (60%)  Hurdle requirement: To pass this subject students must pass the end of semester examination.
In the following sections, details are provided (and will be populated throughout semester) about those assessments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
