<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weekly Study Plan on Topics in Actuarial, Insurance and Finance</title>
    <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weekly Study Plan on Topics in Actuarial, Insurance and Finance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 1 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-1/</guid>
      <description>Week 1 Overview #  This week, we will cover the following topics:
 Introduction to the course (Module 1): what are the broader questions we will answer in this subject, and how are they connected? Collective Risk Modelling (Module 2): how do you work out the distribution of the sum of claims if you can make assumptions about their frequency and severity, and what are typical assumptions for claims frequency?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-2/</guid>
      <description>Week 2 Overview #  This week, we will cover the following topics:
 End of Module 2 (Poisson decomposition, and \((a,b)\) family) Data analysis and descriptive statistics (Module 3): how do get a good sense of the properties of a data set, either graphically or numerically? Selected parametric claim size distributions (Module 3): what are good potential candidates for a describing the data likelihood profile with a parametric function? Fitting of distributions (Module 3): How do we then go about fitting the parameters to a given data set?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-3/</guid>
      <description>Week 3 Overview #  This week, we will cover the following topics:
 End of Section 3.4, covering the most complicated case of left-truncation and right-censoring (with parameters changing potentially with each claim) Model selection (Module 3): how do we assess how good a model fits to data (“goodness-of-fit”)? How do we make a choice? Calculating wihin layers for claim sizes (Module 3): reinsurance, and some policy tranformations (in particular, stop loss / deductibles) lead to different “layers” of claims being covered by different parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-4/</guid>
      <description>Week 4 Overview #  This week, we will cover the following topics, mostly from Module 4:
 Finalising stop-loss calculations Discretisation of continuous distributions (to be able to use Panjer, in particular; see next item) Use of Panjer’s recursion algorithm, which allows us to calculate the exact compound distribution of any random sum, if the frequency follows the \((a,b)\) family Recap of the Normal approximation, as well as translated gamma and lognormal approximations, to be used when one needs a quick approximation, or when only moments are available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-5/</guid>
      <description>Week 5 Overview #  Continuing on with the Claims Modelling component of the subject, which corresponds to the Section 1 of the CS2 syllabus; In particular, we will cover Module 5–Copulas–and
 discuss what stochastic dependence means, how it arises in an insurance context, and discuss some examples; discuss how to extract the mathematical form of a stochastic dependence structure through copulas briefly discuss how to use copulas in practice  Here is the end of week 4 video, which introduces week 5:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-6/</guid>
      <description>Week 6 Overview #  Continuing on with the Claims Modelling component of the subject, which corresponds to the Section 1 of the CS2 syllabus; In particular, we will cover Module 6–Extreme Value Theory–and
 discuss how to work out the limiting distribution of the maximum of a sample; discuss how to work out the limiting distribution of the excess cost of a threshold.  Here is the end of week 5 video, which introduces week 6:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-7/</guid>
      <description>Week 7 Overview #  This week, we will focus on the mid-semester exam
There won’t be lectures, and tutorials will focus on Module 6.
 -- If you wish to watch the embedded videos from Lecture Capture, you need to have logged in and entered Lecture Capture via Canvas once for each session. This is to restrict access to students enrolled at the University of Melbourne only. -- Main references and lectures #  n/a</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-8/</guid>
      <description>Week 8 Overview #  We will introduce the Time Series component of the subject, which corresponds to the Section 2 of the CS2 syllabus
In particular, we will:
 explore some example of time series which we will further analyse later in the time series modules introduce some basic models (which we will review in full detail in Module 9) discuss the concept of “Stationarity” Finally, discuss the estimation of “correlation” in the context of time series (the presence of which, really, is the whole point of time series analysis)   -- If you wish to watch the embedded videos from Lecture Capture, you need to have logged in and entered Lecture Capture via Canvas once for each session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-9/</guid>
      <description>Week 9 Overview #  Note that there is no face to face lecture this week due to unexpected circumstances. Please watch the recorded lectures from Lecture Capture. Thanks for your understanding! Continuing on with the Time Series component of the subject, which corresponds to the Section 2 of the CS2 syllabus; In particular,
 We will revisit regression from the time series context (TS 2.1) We will see how to explore data, and try to “detrend” a time series (TS 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-10/</guid>
      <description>Week 10 Overview #  Continuing on with the Time Series component of the subject, which corresponds to the Section 2 of the CS2 syllabus; In particular, we will
 introduce the PACF; study in detail \(AR(p)\) models; study in detail \(MA(q)\) models.   -- If you wish to watch the embedded videos from Lecture Capture, you need to have logged in and entered Lecture Capture via Canvas once for each session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-11/</guid>
      <description>Week 11 Overview #  Continuing on with the Time Series component of the subject, which corresponds to the Section 2 of the CS2 syllabus; In particular, we will
 study in detail \(ARMA(p,q)\) models; study in detail \(ARIMA(p,d,q)\) models; introduce seasonal \(ARIMA\) models; introduce multivariate autoregressive \(VAR(p)\) models; introduce some additional models mentioned in the CS2 syllabus.  Here is the end of week 10 video, which introduces week 11:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12 Study Plan</title>
      <link>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://topics-actl.netlify.app/docs/0-study-plan/week-12/</guid>
      <description>Week 12 Please fill out the end of subject survey (ESS) here– thanks in advance! Overview #  Continuing on with the Time Series component of the subject, which corresponds to the Section 2 of the CS2 syllabus; In particular, we will
 discuss how to fit the models seen in Module 9 to data sets; discuss how to use those fitted models to perform forecasts.   -- If you wish to watch the embedded videos from Lecture Capture, you need to have logged in and entered Lecture Capture via Canvas once for each session.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
